Guide to the Ezra Pound Papers Addition
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1912-70; Series II; 3; (7 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Articles and Essays
      - "Praefatio" (for unidentified poetry anthology): typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 772)
      - "Private Money": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 773)
      - "Proem": typescript and carbon (Box 33, Folder 774)
      - "Proem." Five Troubadour Songs (arranged by Agnes Bedford): printed text, 1920 (Box 33, Folder 775)
      - "La Sera": proof sheets, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 776)
      - "Social Credit: An Impact" (Money Pamphlets, number 5): printed texts, 1951 (Box 33, Folder 777)
      - The Spirit of Romance (introduction to reprinting): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 778)
      - "Translators of Greek": galley proofs, 1934 (Box 33, Folder 779)
      - "Un Modo di Communicare": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 780)
      - Untitled commentary on program of concerts: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 781)
      - Unidentified manuscript: typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 782)
      - Newspaper articles: photocopies, 1943-35, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 783)
    - Interviews
      - RAI interviews (notes and text): holographs and typescript (Box 33, Folder 784-85)
      - Newspaper interviews: printed text, 1931 (Box 33, Folder 786)
    - Letters
      - "Notatki Materialy: Ezra Pound's Letters to a Polish Scholar" (Stanislaw (Jankowski), 1970 (Box 34, Folder 787)
      - "Gli Scrittori Del Figullio": printed text, [1944] (Box 34, Folder 788)
      - "Volitionist Economics"; printed text, [1931] (Box 34, Folder 789)
      - Letters to editors, 1928, 1934 (Box 34, Folder 790)
    - Other Writings
      - Comments on Olga Rudge: holograph notes, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 791-92)
      - Radio broadcasts
        - Comments: typescript, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 793)
        - Text of broadcast: typescript, carbon, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 794)
      - Spoleto readings: holograph transcriptions, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 795)
      - Personal recollections, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 796)
      - Outline for unidentified work or documentary
      - Copy exercises, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 797)
      - Fragments, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 798-800)
    - Notebooks and Notes
      - Notebook (marked "First Walking Tour in France 1912") (Box 34, Folder 801)
      - Notebook (marked "E. P... .1917/ 1st World War") (Box 34, Folder 802)
      - Notebook (essay review of works by Ford Madox Ford, with other notes), n.d. (Box 34, Folder 803)
      - Other notebooks (various topics), 1925-66, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 804-11)
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 812-27)
- Personal Papers, 1903-72; Series III; 3.5; (8 boxes)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is arranged alphabetically by subject headings, then chronologically within files.
  - Address books and lists (Box 36, Folder 828-30)
  - Appointments, 1943, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 831)
  - Awards and honors, 1969, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 832)
  - Biographical material, 1965-66, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 833)
  - Blotting paper (one group marked E. P.'s blotters/ war period"), n.d. (Box 36, Folder 834)
  - Calling cards
    - Ezra Pound (Box 36, Folder 835)
    - Others, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 836)
  - Conferences and readings (with or about Pound), 1933-67, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 837)
  - Currency ("the remains of my grandfather's fortune") (Box 36, Folder 838)
  - Exhibitions and special programs (catalogues, publicity, invitations), 1914-83, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 839-42)
  - Exhibitions and special programs (catalogues, publicity, invitations), 1914-83, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 843-46)
  - Exile: Prospectus, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 847)
  - Fabric swatch (with note by Olga Rudge?), n.d. (Box 37, Folder 848)
  - Financial papers, 1926-87, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 849-52)
    See also: Radio speeches, Box 39, folder 896
  - Flowers, pressed, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 853)
  - Food lists, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 854)
  - Gaudier-Brzeska material, 1964-72 (Box 37, Folder 855)
  - "Iphigenia Among the Taurians" (University of Pennsylvania production): printed program, 1903 (Box 37, Folder 856)
  - Landor, Walter Savage. Autograph letter, signed, with typed copy and engraving (Box 37, Folder 857)
  - Lectures (The Polytechnic): publicity, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 858)
  - Legal papers, 1941-69, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 859-60)
  - Lewis, Wyndham. Publicity material (Box 37, Folder 861)
  - Magazines and journals, 1928-69 (Box 37, Folder 862)
  - Medical reports and prescriptions, 1953-72, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 863-64)
  - Membership cards, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 865)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1919-80, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 866-74)
  - Notes, c.1920-72, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 875-82)
  - Pamphlets and brochures (Box 39, Folder 883)
  - Passports, 1927-72 (Box 39, Folder 884)
  - Permissions, 1968-69 (Box 39, Folder 885)
  - Photographs and sketches
    - Ezra Pound (original photographs), 1969, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 886)
    - Ezra Pound (reproductions and clippings) (Box 39, Folder 887)
    - Parker Tyler (photograph by Carl Van Vechten), 1935 (Box 39, Folder 888)
    - Others, 1961-70, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 889)
    - Sketches of Pound (Box 39, Folder 890)
    - Original watercolor sketches by E. E. Cummings, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 891)
    - Other sketches, 1962-65 (Box 39, Folder 892)
    - Cuala Press: handcolored card (Box 39, Folder 893)
  - Postcards, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 894)
  - Questionnaires, 1964, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 895)
  - Radio speeches: payment vouchers from Ministero Della Cultura Populare, 1941-43 (Box 39, Folder 896-99)
  - Seals of Ezra Pound (Box 39, Folder 900)
  - Spoleto Festival (various material), 1970 (Box 39, Folder 901)
  - Stamps, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 902)
  - Stationery (Ezra Pound) (Box 39, Folder 903)
  - Testimonial for Joan Fitzgerald, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 904)
  - Teeth (Ezra Pound) (Box 40, Folder 905)
  - Travel documents (receipts, itineraries, etc.), 1939-69, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 906)
  - Weston, Harding: Certificate of Commission in New York State Volunteers
  - Will (codicil) and related letters, 1964-67, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 907)
  - Writings about Ezra Pound
    Articles and Essays
    - Arnold, Heinz. "Der Dichter Ezra Pound", 1965 (Box 40, Folder 908)
    - Hesse, Eva. "Postscriptum" (with letter), 1966 (Box 40, Folder 909)
    - Others, 1931-77, n.d (Box 40, Folder 910-13)
    - News clippings, 1914-70, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 914-17)
  - Writings of Others
    - Aponte, Salvatore, "La Guerra Degli Inglesi in Francia": printed text (with notes by Ezra Pound), 1941 (Box 40, Folder 918)
    - Bunting, Basil (?). "Ehen Fugaces": typescript, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 919)
    - Bunting, Basil. "Narcissus, my numerous cancellations prefer", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 920)
    - Cournos, John. Miscellaneous poems: typescript, 1964, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 921)
    - "Diario di Un Ufficiale Austriaco Ignoto Rinvenuto Sul Campo di Battaglia" (with translation): typescripts, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 922)
    - Drummond, John. "Suggested Corrections for a Reprinting of 'An Introduction to the Economic Nature of the United States'": typescript, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 923)
    - Duncan, Ronald. "Ars Poetica (No.1)": typescript, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 924)
    - Dunning, Ralph Cheever. Poems: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 925)
    - Eliot, T. S. The Wasteland (excerpt): typescript, photocopy (Box 40, Folder 926)
    - Fitzgerald, Robert. "Iliad I": typescript, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 927)
    - Fuller, Buckminster. Keynote address, Vision 65: printed text, 1965 Oct (Box 40, Folder 928)
    - "Guerra e alla Pace in Cina" ("Dischi-Spettacola": E. M. I.- Italiana): typescript and photocopy (Box 40, Folder 929)
    - Oppen, George. "21 Poems": typescript, [1930] (Box 40, Folder 930)
    - Pound, Omar. Miscellaneous poems: printed texts, 1968-71 (Box 40, Folder 931)
    - "Present Day Literature in Italy: typescript (with some corrections in Pound's hand) (Box 40, Folder 932)
    - Others, 1918-72, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 933-44)
    - Others, 1903-72, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 945-55)
    - Musical scores
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1920-84, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 956-973)
- Oversize, Dates 1862-1965; 3; (3 boxes)
  Oversize contains material from Writings and Personal Papers, the items arranged in the sequence in which they appear in these series.
  - Writings
    - Musical Compositions
      - Cavalcanti
        - Musical score (various drafts): holograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 974-87)
        - Musical score (incomplete): holograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 988)
      - "Ghuidoni's Sonata"
        - Musical score (incomplete): holograph, 1931 Oct (Box 44, Folder 989)
        - Musical score (3rd Movement: "Freely adapted for string orchestra" by Tibor Serly): holograph, carbon, 1938 (Box 44, Folder 990)
      - "Hommage à Froissart": holograph musical score, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 991)
      - La Testament de Villon
        - Musical score (various drafts); holograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 992-93)
        - Musical score (various drafts): holograph, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 994-1007)
        - Musical score (incomplete): holograph, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1008)
        - "Paroles de Villon": holograph musical score and printed libretto, 1926 (Box 45, Folder 1009)
        - Note by G. Menotti on staging: holograph, carbon, 1965 Jul 7 (Box 45, Folder 1010)
  - Personal Papers
    - Weston, Harding. Certificate of commission in the New York State Volunteers, 1962 Mar 4 (Box 46, Folder 1011)
    - Unidentified musical scores, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1012-20)
    - Outline for unidentifed work, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1021)